let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1.,
        question: 'SDLC stands for..',
        answer: 'A. software development life cycle',
        options: [
            'A. software development life cycle',
            'B. system development life cycle',
            'C. software design life cycle',
            'D. system design life cycle'
        ]
    },
    
    {
        numb: 2.,
        question: 'Which model is selected if user is involved in all the phases of SDLC ?',
        answer: 'C. RAD model',
        options: [
            'A. Waterfall model',
            'B. prototyping model',
            'C. RAD model',
            'D. both (B) and (C)'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3.,
        question: 'The spiral model was originally proposed by',
        answer: 'B. Barry Boehm',
        options: [
            'A. IBM',
            'B. Barry Boehm',
            'C. Pressman',
            'D. Royce'
        ]
    },
    
    {
        numb: 4.,
        question: 'RAD stands for..',
        answer: 'B. Rapid application development',
        options: [
            'A. Relative application development',
            'B. Rapid application development',
            'C. Rapid application document',
            'D. All of the mentioned'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5.,
        question: 'Which is not one of the types of prototype of prototyping model?',
        answer: 'C. Diagonal prototype',
        options: [
            'A. horizontal prototype',
            'B. vertical prototype',
            'C. Diagonal prototype',
            'D. Domain prototype'
        ]
    },
    
    {
        numb: 6.,
        question: 'RAD model has ',
        answer: 'C. 5 phases',
        options: [
            'A. 2 phases',
            'B. 3 phases',
            'C. 5 phases',
            'D. 6 phases'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7.,
        question: 'What is attributes of good software?',
        answer: 'D. software maintainability & functionality',
        options: [
            'A. software maintainability',
            'B. software functionality',
            'C. software development',
            'D. software maintainability & functionality'
        ]
    },
    
    {
        numb: 8.,
        question: 'Which of these software engineering activities are not a part of software processes ?',
        answer: 'A. Software dependence',
        options: [
            'A. Software dependence',
            'B. Software development',
            'C. Software validation',
            'D. Software specification'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9.,
        question: 'Which phase of the RUP is used to establish a business case for the system?',
        answer: 'D. Inception',
        options: [
            'A. Transition',
            'B. Elaboration',
            'C. Construction',
            'D. Inception'
        ]
    },
    
    {
        numb: 10.,
        question: 'The longer a fault exists in software',
        answer: 'D. all of the mentioned',
        options: [
            'A. the more tedious its removal becomes',
            'B. the more costly it is to detect and correct',
            'C. the less likely is to be properly connected',
            'D. all of the mentioned'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11.,
        question: 'How many phases are there in scrum?',
        answer: 'B. Three',
        options: [
            'A. Two',
            'B. Three',
            'C. Four',
            'D. Seven'
        ]
    },
    
    {
        numb: 12.,
        question: 'which of the following activities of a generic process framework provides a feedback report?',
        answer: 'D. Deployment',
        options: [
            'A. Communication',
            'B. Planning',
            'C. Modelling and construction',
            'D. Deployment'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13.,
        question: 'Purpose of process is to deliver software',
        answer: 'D. both (A) and (B)',
        options: [
            'A. in time',
            'B. with acceptable quality',
            'C. that is cost efficient',
            'D. both (A) and (B)'
        ]
    },
    
    {
        numb: 14.,
        question: 'Four types of changes are encountered during the support phase.Which one of the following is not one that falls into such category?',
        answer: 'A. Translation',
        options: [
            'A. Translation',
            'B. Correction',
            'C. Adaptation',
            'D. Prevention'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15.,
        question: 'Identify a fourth generation language (4GL) from the given below',
        answer: 'C. Unix shell',
        options: [
            'A. FORTRAN',
            'B. COBOL',
            'C. Unix shell',
            'D. C++'
        ]
    },
    
    {
        numb: 16.,
        question: '4GL is an example of ____ processing.',
        answer: 'D. Both (B) and (C)',
        options: [
            'A. white box',
            'B. Black box',
            'C. Functional',
            'D. Both (B) and (C)'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17.,
        question: 'The 4GT model is a package of ___',
        answer: 'B. software tools',
        options: [
            'A. case tools',
            'B. software tools',
            'C. software programs',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    
    {
        numb: 18.,
        question: 'Which of the following is not a type of a 4GL? One-originating ____',
        answer: 'A. on Lisp machine',
        options: [
            'A. on Lisp machine',
            'B. on report generators',
            'C. from database query languages',
            'D. from GUI creators'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19.,
        question: 'which one of the following is not a software process quality?',
        answer: 'B. Portability',
        options: [
            'A. Productivity',
            'B. Portability',
            'C. Timeliness',
            'D. Visibility'
        ]
    },
    
    {
        numb: 20.,
        question: '___ & _____ are two kinds of software products.',
        answer: 'C. Generic , Customised',
        options: [
            'A. CAD , CAM',
            'B. Firmware , Embedded',
            'C. Generic , Customised',
            'D. None of the mentioned'
        ]
    }
    
]